43691 Frost Court (571) 207-5025 <u>Ashburn, VA 20147 vzeudoua@verizon.net</u>

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

A "Gladiator in a Suit" with more than 22 years of experience as a strategic new business development/capture executive with extensive program management, management consulting, and business process improvement skills. Mr. Manuel-Scott is a Senior Business Development Executive and Business Analyst with over eighteen years experience managing people and resources. He has a demonstrated track record of managing the business issues and data challenges of clients as well as identifying their strengths and weaknesses while suggesting areas of improvement. He leads transition planning and implementations for major engagements, reviews and edits requirements, specifications, suggests business processes re-engineering and improvement strategies, and provides recommendations related to proposed solutions.

CLEARANCES

Active Top Secret/SCI with full scope polygraph

EDUCATION

Masters Certificate, Project Management, George Washington University 2004 EDS University, Post Baccalaureate, Global Sales Institute, Shipley Sales Capture 2002 Bachelor of Arts, History, Morris Brown College 1996 U.S. Navy, Naval Technical Training Center, Yeoman "A" School, 1988

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

RONIN IT Services, LLC, Leesburg, VA

July 2005 to Present

Co-Founder, Principal and Managing Partner

- Directs and manages sales and operations of a minority and veteran-owned small disadvantaged professional services company in 2005, providing strategic business process re-engineering and improvement, program management, and IT management consulting (Decision Support, Transformation Services, Disaster Recovery/COOP and Emergency Management Planning) to clients in the federal marketplace
- Principal Project Team leader responsible for Analysis of multi-faceted Intelligence programs. Compiles data to assess Analysis and Solution Definition, Technical Recommendations and Testing, and Project Execution
- Assists in the facilitation of team and client interaction pushing creative thinking beyond the boundaries of existing industry practices and mindsets
- Drives team to develop solutions for customers that reduces costs, creates greater efficiencies and transforms the way clients conduct business
- Leader of 54 highly skilled professionals responsible for positioning and maintaining RONIN's business within Department of Homeland Security EAGLE, Department of Justice, Department of State, and Intelligence Agencies
- Developed information technology solutions and business process improvement solutions in the high performance computing environment, deployable systems, secure communications, biometrics, and information assurance.
 Developed Centers of Excellence for enhanced capability in IPv6 and Service Oriented Architecture
- Awarded \$175M IDIQ for FBI Information Technology Operations Contract (ITOC) effort and provides Strategic Business Development Consulting Services to small, mid-tier and large firms in IC community
- Awarded \$6.6B IDIQ for DIA Solutions for Information Technology Enterprise (SITE) as a key partner to a tier-one systems integrator and providing Business Process Improvement Support - \$147M Enterprise Operations Task Order and \$197M Customer Engagement Support Services Task Order
- Awarded \$30B FBI IT Triple-S and \$2.2B DOJ ITSS-IV Contracts as a primary subcontractor to a major products and services systems integrator
- Awarded \$450M NGA eSMARTS Contract as primary subcontractor to a tier-one systems integrator
 Selective New Business Capture Engagements include:

MicroTech, Vienna, VA

Vice President, Justice and Intelligence Programs (Consultant)

- Program Manager and Business Developer with operational responsibility overseeing \$30B FBI IT Triple S contract vehicle and associated task orders (CSTOR 11) Quantico TITCU effort
- Created synergy among FBI subcontractors and new linkages among contractors within the classified environment

SELECTED NEW BUSINESS CAPTURE ENGAGEMENTS (Continued)

- Identified and qualified a \$368M pipeline of opportunities across Department of Justice, Homeland Security, and Classified Agencies focusing on Virtual Desktop Initiatives, Energy Efficient Portable MicroPodd DR/COOP containers, and Transformational Support services
- Fostered growth within Classified Agencies and bolstered partnerships for company executives by gaining 6 clearances up to TS/SCI for senior management

NATEK Incorporated, Dulles, VA

Principal Consultant

- As an independent consultant, engaged to manage and oversee \$36M organization with 175 personnel by recapturing \$100M incumbent contract at USDA International Technology Services division, and prepare the company for the next phase of evolution including acquisitions
- Streamlined corporate operations, increased team member productivity, corporate branding, recruiting, and overall moral
- Responsible for managing all aspects of internal and external new business management, existing IDIQ/GWACs and winning new business under IT Schedule 70, DHS EAGLE, Encore II, ITES-2S, Alliant Small Business, 8(a) STARS, TIPSS-4, and
- Hired strategic personnel and qualified \$740M pipeline of opportunities and captured new business in Civilian Agencies, DoD, and Classified Agencies

Alion Science and Technology, Inc., McLean, VA

Senior Consultant - Operational Solutions Group

- Engaged to identify and qualify strategic pipeline of opportunities at \$25M or higher within Human Systems Integration, Modeling and Simulation, Systems Engineering, Intelligence, Wireless Spectrum Engineering, and Information Technology and Software Development
- Secured 3-year \$45M sole source contract at the Modeling and Simulation Information Analysis Center (MSIAC)
- Identified strategic sales pipeline opportunities by \$1.4B at AFRL, DARPA, NGA, CIA, DTRA, DISA, FBI, USSTRATCOM, ONR, JIEDDO, NSA, and OSD

High Performance Technology, Inc., Reston, VA

Senior Consultant – Advanced Systems Group

- Lead business development activities that require special access and extensive expertise in the Intelligence community
- Provided support by utilizing contacts in Army Logistic, Sustainment and Research Development programs, and Navy PEO's including DARPA, IARPA, NRL and NASIC developing solutions in Modeling and Simulation, Enterprise Architecture, Research and Development, Visualization, and High Performance Computing
- Applied engineering, technical project development/execution, business development and financial oversight in response to C4ISR business opportunities
- Increased strategic sales pipeline of classified opportunities by \$290M
- Identified and secured tactical and strategic teaming agreements at CIA, DIA, DHS NGA, NRO, ODNI and FBI with agreed upon Exhibit A's that define roles and responsibilities

G&B Solutions, Inc., a Wholly-Owned Subsidiary of VSE Corporation, Reston, VA

Consultant - Vice President Business Development

- Responsible for strategically transforming former 8(a) company with strategic identification, capture and closure of new business in DoD, DHS and Intelligence Agencies
- In under 3 months, lead organization to \$8.9M contract award at Treasury's FINCEN; \$3.4M contract award at FBI; and \$1.7M contract award at Bureau of Labor Statistics
- Managed Business Development staff of 7 people in Proposal Development, Capture Management, Contracts and Pricing
- Collaborated with VSE Corporation sister companies to qualify and target a pipeline of opportunities over \$250M including Net Centric Enterprise Services (NCES), Information Systems Engineering, and DoD Architectural Framework (DoDAF) system engineering support

SELECTED NEW BUSINESS CAPTURE ENGAGEMENTS (Continued)

SRA International, Fairfax, VA

Principal Consultant - C3I Intelligence

- Consultant responsible for implementing Sole Source Subroutine throughout the Intelligence Community, DoDIIS,
 C3I, Global Command and Control Systems (GCCS) and Joint Command and Control (JC2)
- Targeted and secured \$19M sole source contract within classified agency (opportunity fully funded for 1 year)
- Lead team \$10M National Gang Intelligence Center, and \$84.2M NGA NDPE-Move Planning and Execution awards
- Established trusted advisor relationship with customers in Geospatial Intelligence and Intelligence Analysis environment that lead to new GIS and Analyst Support contracts

Raytheon Information Solutions, Intelligence and Information Services, Reston, VA

Senior Consultant - Director Strategic Capture Management

- Consultant Pre-qualified, Positioned and Lead Law Enforcement and Homeland Security initiatives
- Lead capture team to win \$88M FBI National Data Exchange (NDEx) contract at the Criminal Justice Information Services (CJIS) in Clarksburg, WV
- Managed P&L and lead team of three business developers responsible for growing newest company business unit
- Developed information technology and business process improvement solutions in the high performance computing
 environment, deployable systems, secure communications, biometric and information assurance for customers in
 DOJ Organized Crime Drug Enforcement Task Force (OCDETF), DHS Intelligence Analysis (IA), and ODNI

Keane Federal Systems, McLean, VA

August 2004 to June 2005

Senior Account Executive

- Lead account team to \$68M of the \$300M NOAA Advanced Weather Integrated Program System (AWIPS) contract
- Supported Strategic Business Intelligence for DOJ Information Technology Support Services (ITSS-3) contract
- Client Solutions Consultant responsible for growing new business in DHS, DOJ and Intelligence agencies

EDS - U.S. Government Solutions, Herndon, VA

December 2001 to August 2004

Client Sales Executive

- Managed tactical and strategic new business development activities of key agency accounts with focus on sales and delivery of services including \$30M IT Consolidation effort at Department of Commerce
- Under broad direction, initiated, planned, implemented and successfully closed new contracts that encompass valueadded technology solutions ranging from short-term to complex multi-year and multi-service engagement
- Developed Customer Relationship Management (CRM) flow diagrams and defined content and training curriculum for tier 2 and 3 call center representatives for sensitive All-Source Intel Analysis and Enterprise Network environments
- Developed and implemented emergency management, business continuity and disaster recovery strategy with \$7M in sales

Choice Hotels International, Silver Spring, MD

December 1999 to December 2001

National Sales Director – Government/Military

- Created an in-depth business plan and developed new division in Government/Military sales identifying competitors' sales strategies, initiatives and relative sales position recommending tactics that match customers' growth patterns and needs resulting in 48 new accounts, \$74 million in revenue and 11% growth
- Consulted leading domestic and international travel policy advisors including the Travel Industry Association of America
 (TIA) to craft Choice's go-to-market strategy in the wake of the September 11th attacks; results culminated in
 exponential growth

Kevin M. Manuel-Scott, P.C., Legal Researchers, Montgomery Village, MD

February 1997 to July 2003

President/CEO

 Successfully managed and sold legal research and consulting services business providing support for small businesses, case law research, contracts and business law documents

SELECTED NEW BUSINESS CAPTURE ENGAGEMENTS (Continued)

- Managed a group of eight highly skilled paralegals and law students providing value added services to clients
- Engagements decreased total cost of ownership allowing customers to focus on growing their business

College Positions and Internships, Atlanta, GA

August 1993 to May 1996

Paralegal, Legal Researcher and Case Management Supervisor

- U.S. Attorney's Office, Organized Crime Drug Task Force Unit, Northern District of Georgia, Atlanta, GA
- Immigration and Naturalization Service, Litigation Division, Northern District of Georgia, Atlanta, GA
- Office of Imogene L. Walker, Magistrate Judge, DeKalb County, Decatur, GA

SKILLS

- Certified Paralegal, Six Sigma, Business Process Reengineering and Improvement, BSI ISO 9000:2001Specialist, Contingency Planning
- Financial and Business Management Analyst. PMO Implementation, MetaStorm® Business Process Designer
- Expert Choice v.11 Enterprise Portfolio Analysis, Collaborative Decision Support including Predictive Analysis
- Independent Emergency Management Auditor and Planner, Utilizes Scenario Based Engineering (SBE), Enterprise 2.0
- Transition and Training Specialist in Multi-Agency acquisitions, DoD 5000, DCID, FAR/DFAR
- Critical Infrastructure Protection, Functional Expert (ITIL v3), Capital Planning Investment Control (OMB 300/53)

ORGANIZATIONS

Vice President of Development/Board Member, 100 Black Men of Greater Washington, DC 2007 to present Member, National Military Intelligence Association, Potomac Chapter 2006 to present President/Director, Joyce-Gillespie-Harrington Educational & Charitable Foundation, Inc. 2004 to present Member, Program Management Institute, Washington, DC Chapter 2004 to present Member, Armed Forces Communications and Electronics Association 2001 to present Member, Alpha Phi Alpha Fraternity, Inc. 1996 to present

AWARDS

National Defense Ribbon
Meritorious Promotion, Captain USS WASP (LHD 1) and Secretary of the Navy
The Beacon – Military Life, First Crew Member/Plankowner Award
Morris Brown College Academic Honor Student
Distinguished Leadership Award – Joyce-Gillespie-Harrington Educational and Charitable Foundation, Inc.

CONTRIBUTING PUBLICATIONS

"Leadership and Innovation: Harnessing the New Forces Used by Business to Succeed" 2013, written by Melvin B. Greer, Jr., Senior Fellow and Chief Strategist at Lockheed Martin

"Software as a Service Inflection Point: Using Cloud Computing to Achieve Business Agility" 2009, written by Melvin B. Greer, Senior Research Engineer and Certified Enterprise Architect at Lockheed Martin

COMMUNITY SERVICE

- Gifted \$30,000 to George Mason University Foundation to establish the Paul Robeson Saturday Leadership Academy through the Joyce-Gillespie-Harrington Educational and Charitable Foundation, Inc.
- Alpha Phi Alpha Martin Luther King, Jr., National Memorial Project Foundation
- Mentored and tutored teens diagnosed with Attention Deficient Disorder and Hyperactivity (ADHD) in anger management and conflict resolution